

Koushik Puppala

Full Stack Developer | Freelancer

📞 +91 9492993737 👂 Raichur, Karnataka, India 🛮 in LinkedIn 🦪 GitHub

🛱 Discord 🎔 Twitter 🕲 Skype

■ Introduction

I am pursuing my B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering at the Indian Institute of Information Technology, Raichur. As a passionate full-stack web developer, I regularly work in that capacity and lead my institute's Google Developer Student Clubs. Currently, I am working on fascinating projects that include the creation of a Discord bot and many full-stack web apps.

My expertise has given me a good understanding of front-end and back-end technologies, allowing me to design unique, user-friendly software solutions. I am careful and strive for perfection in whatever I do. As I progress, I am excited to professionally apply my abilities and expertise as a Full Stack Developer.

Education

Computer Science and Engineer (B.Tech)

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Raichur ☑ 2020 – present | Karnataka, India

M.P.C Intermediate

Tirumala Junior College ☑ 2018 – 2020 | Rajahmundry, India

Skills

Languages

JavaScript | TypeScript | Markdown | HTML | CSS

Full Stack Development

React | Next.js | Express.js | Node.js | MongoDB | Figma

Tools

GitHub | Firebase | Docker | Canva | AWS

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer (Task Lead)

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Raichur

Aug 2022 – present | Raichur, India

- Led a team to develop and maintain our college website, foster collaboration, and achieve project objectives.
- Oversaw allocating responsibilities, providing guidance and support to team members, resulting in increased productivity and a cohesive work environment.
- Collaborated with faculty, staff, and student organizations to gather requirements and ensure the website met their needs.

Full Stack Developer Internship

TGH Technologies Pvt Ltd ☑

Aug 2022 – Sep 2022 | Remote, India

- I used React, Figma for the front end, Node.js for the backend, MongoDB for the database, and Firebase for push notifications.
- I added a few features, such as the approval of leave requests by the requested reg: admin, respective manager, and a few push notifications in both the front and back end.

Full Stack Web Developer (Task Master)

Dec 2020 – Aug 2022 | Raichur, India

Indian Institute of Information Technology Raichur 🛮

- I have collaborated closely with a dedicated team to develop and maintain our college website, contributing to its success and functionality.
- Actively participated in team meetings, offering valuable insights and ideas for improving the website's design, functionality, and overall user engagement. Adapted quickly to new technologies and tools used in web development, continuously expanding my skill set and contributing to the team's technical proficiency.

- I have developed a solid understanding of web development principles, user experience best practices, and project management methodologies through hands-on experience and active learning.

Certificates

The Ultimate Full Stack Web Development Course □ | The Complete Front-End Web Development Course □

Server Authentication using Express and NodeJS 🗵 | The Complete Full-Stack JavaScript Course 🖸

30 days Google Cloud Program Certificate ☑ | Python for Beginners (2022) ☑

♂ Interests

Open Source | Full Stack Development | MERN Stack Development | Discord Bots Development

Android App Development | Game Development | Artificial Intelligence | Machine Learning

Projects

SafeRideX Mar 2023 – present

Blockchain-based Cab Booking System | Mini Project

- It was built using the latest technologies for the front and back end and the blockchain.
- The website was on Nextjs, Tailwindcss, and Mui. The server was on Nodejs and Express.
- MongoDB as a database, Thirdwed for blockchain, and Firebase for authentication and file storage.

Council of Students Affairs Official Website

Jun 2021 – present

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Raichur

- The website was on Jekyll and hosted on GitHub pages.
- This includes all the information, events, clubs, and other opportunities students should know about.

Official Website ☑ Jan 2021 – present

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Raichur

- The website was on Jekyll and hosted on Vercel.
- This website contains all the information about admission, careers, faculty, research, facilities, etc.

Avengers Assemble ☑ May 2021

Discord Bots website and dashboard

- This website and dashboard for a Discord bot have more than 250 commands and are still under improvement. The website was on EJS (Embedded JavaScript). The server was on Node.js and Express. The database was on MongoDB.
- It has a dashboard so that changing or customizing the parameters for the bot will be simple. To access the Discord Bot Dashboard and find the server that they can run on, we are using the Discord Login.

Avenger Bot ☑ Feb 2021

Discord Bot | Multi-purpose

- One of my greatest Discord bots, created with Javascript and Discord.js. It features 13+ categories and more than 250 commands. It is an ever-expanding, open-source Discord bot that is customizable.
- A wide range of features includes Welcome and Farewell messages; extensive logging for 37 events; Slash Commands; advanced auto-moderation; audio filters for music plugins, custom playlist support; giveaways, reaction roles, and more. In addition, more than 40 options can be changed!

E.D.I.T.H Screen Recorder

May 2021 – Aug 2021

Windows Desktop App

- This application for screen recording was made for our semester project. Javascript, HTML, and Electron were used in its construction.
- Google Drive Authentication and Google Login are available in this application. If the user has signed up with Google, the recorded video will be automatically posted to their Google Drive.

Koushik Puppala

Musics_DJ ☑ Dec 2020 – May 2021

Discord Bot | Music Player

- I created this open-source Discord bot using JavaScript and Discord.js.
- It has numerous music controls, including volume, play, pauses, and skip. In addition, both playlist commands and filter commands are plentiful.

Portfolio ☑ Dec 2020 – present

First Project

- This is my first project created when I started learning web development.
- It moved from basic HTML to advance Nextjs code with Typescript.
- MongoDB as a database. Open Source project, available on GitHub.

A Organizations

Google Developer Student Clubs 🛮

Jul 2022 – present | Raichur, India

Google Developer Student Clubs Lead

- Led and managed the GDSC Club, a community passionate about technology and focused on fostering innovation and collaboration. Coordinated and supervised club activities, including workshops, coding competitions, and speaker events, ensuring successful execution and impactful outcomes.
- I developed and delivered presentations on emerging technologies, programming languages, and industry trends, sharing knowledge and fostering a culture of continuous learning within the club.
- I coordinated with other student clubs and organizations on campus to collaborate on joint events, expanding the club's reach and promoting interdisciplinary collaboration.

Indian Institute of Information Technology Raichur

Sep 2021 – Aug 2022 | Raichur, India

CodeSoc Club Coordinator

- I coordinated and managed the activities of the Codesoc Club, a vibrant community dedicated to promoting coding culture.
- I organized regular coding workshops, and coding competitions, providing valuable learning opportunities for club members. In addition, I managed the club's budget, allocating resources effectively to support club initiatives and events.

Google Developer Student Clubs IIIT Raichur 🛭

Sep 2021 – May 2022 | Remote, India

Frontend Lead (GDSC Core Team)

- I led the front-end development initiatives of the GDSC Club, overseeing a team and driving the successful execution of various projects.
- I regularly stayed updated with the latest trends and advancements in front-end development, sharing knowledge with the team and organizing workshops or training sessions.
- I am also a Facilitator of the Andriod app development study jam by GDSC India.